

ABOUT

Hello! I am Abdullah Berkay Bayındır. I am a sophomore undergraduate Electrical and Electronics Engineer Student with strong interest in RF and embedded systems.

I am currently pursuing an Electrical and Electronics Engineering degree in Turkey also searching for professional experience. Excellent time management abilities, strong communication skills and superb problem solving skills.

COMMINUCATION

E-MAIL:

bayindirberkay@gmail.com

LINKEDIN:

linkedin.com/in/abdullahberkaybayindir

GITHUB:

github.com/bkbyndr

INSTAGRAM:

instagram.com/unclebk_/

HOBBYS AND INTERESTS

Amateur Astronomy Learning About Old Turkic History Playing and Watching Basketball Travelling

LANGUAGES

English

Professional Proficiency

German

Intermediate Proficiency

Turkish

Native Proficiency

ABDULLAH BERKAY BAYINDIR

ACADEMIC BACKGROUND

TOBB Economy and Technology University, Ankara Turkey 2019 – Ongoing

Faculty of Engineering

Courses Taken: Logical Čircuit Design (Verilog), Communication Systems, Computer Programming (C, C++), Probablity Theory for Electrical Engineers, Analog Electronic Circuits, Electromagnetic Wave Theory, Signals and Systems, Microprocessors, Control Systems. **GPA:** 3.65/4.00

Student Clubs: IEEE TOBB ETU, Google Developer Students Club

Kalaba Anatolian High School, Ankara, Turkey Department of Science

I was the captain of the school's basketball team. **GPA:** 93/100

EMPLOYMENT EXPERIENCE

ESEN System Integration, Ankara, Turkey Long Term Intern

24 May 2021 - 06 September 2021

- Did some research about fundamentals of RF and Microwave Systems
- ✓ Gain basic knowledge of RF/Wireless lab equipment such as Network Vector Analyzer, Analog Signal Generator, and Spectrum Analyzer.
- ✓ Used AWR Microwave Office circuit design software for circuit design and testing.

Konelsis Control Systems, Ankara, Turkey

June 2019 – July 2019

I have completed this internship in Konelsis before starting to university. Being there, I have seen the production field and learned some basic information about my major.

PROJECTS

Implementation of the Advanced Encryption Standard using Verilog

With a focus on resource utilization efficiency and pipelining, I have assisted the team for implementation of Advanced Encryption Standard using Verilog.

Designing a Five Staged Power Amplifier and Forming a PCB Layout

Designed a five staged power amplifier with 1000 voltage gain, a bandwidth between 20 Hz - 1 MHz and 2 W RMS power at the load while using common elements like emitter follower, common emitter and Class AB Power Amplifier. In addition, created a PCB layout from the five staged amplifiers schematic using AutoCAD Eagle.

SKILLS

